### **STEEVEN MEDINA > SENIOR QA ENGINEER**

I am an experienced Software QA Analyst with over 4 years of expertise in creating and executing test cases, automating processes, and effectively detecting defects for high-volume companies. I am known for my creative problem-solving abilities and am an expert in execution. I am deeply committed to the principles of continuous improvement and consistently strive to enhance software quality and reliability.

# Skills

#### **Programming Languages:**

C#, .NET, Java, JavaScript

#### **Operating Systems:**

Windows, Linux, OSX

#### Databases:

SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle

#### **Test Types:**

Integration Test, Functional Test, Automation Test, E2E Testing, Regression Test, Exploration Test, API Test, Smoke Test, Mobile Testing.

### **Testing & Development Tools:**

Selenium, Appium, Cypress, TestNG, Postman, Ready API

## **Testing Processes:**

Requirement Analysis, Test Plan Creation, Test Case Creation, Test Case Execution, Defect Logging, Defect Fix and Re-verification, Prepare Test Cases, Write Test Scripts, Execute Test Collection or Plan, Maintenance Test Collection

#### Management tools:

Jira, Confluence, Microsoft TFS, GitLab, BitBucket, Git, Grafana, New Relic

#### Methodologies:

Waterfall, Scrum

#### Other:

JBoss, TomCat, Xampp, ISS, XRay for Jira, Vray for Jira

## Professional Experience

## Senior QA Engineer

#### Alphapoint (2022 - Present)

Alphapoint is a leading blockchain technology company, specializing in providing solutions for digital asset exchanges and tokenization of assets.

- Analyzes requirements and user stories, created test cases, and executed test cases.
- Responsible for all QA processes and the QA life cycle for the Chivo Wallet App, Web Site, and APIs.
- Creates a test plan encompassing Automation, Functional, Regression, Exploration, Smoke, and E2E testing.
- Tracks defects, errors, bugs, and glitches in the applications.
- Maintaines the automated test plans.

- Automates APIs using Postman and Thunder Client, Web Portals with Cypress, and Mobile applications with Java, Selenium, and Appium.
- Reviews testing procedures, analyzed test results, and generated test reports.
- Collaborates with technical and product teams to define acceptance criteria for existing and new functionality and determine manual or automated tests as required.
- Maintaines a Test Plan covering functional testing.
- Utilizes Jira for issue reporting and Confluence for documentation.
- Leads the QA team, overseeing testing and continuous improvement to ensure impeccable product outcomes.

## IT Automation Engineer II

### CONDUENT (2020 - 2022)

Conduent provides digital solutions and services across various sectors, delivering exceptional results through technology like cloud computing, AI, and automation.

- Analyzed requirements and user stories, created test cases, and executed test cases.
- Worked with Team Foundation Server, SharePoint, Reporting Services, and Desktop Applications.
- Created a comprehensive test plan covering Automation, Functional, Regression, Exploration, Smoke, and E2E testing.
- Tracked defects, errors, bugs, and glitches in the APIs or applications.
- Developed Automated test steps in ReadyAPI and Postman collections.
- Automated APIs with Postman and JavaScript
- Automated Web Applications with Selenium and Java.
- Maintained the automated test plans and collections.
- Followed Automation test scripts in pipelines on TFS.
- Ensured the maintenance of a Test Plan encompassing functional testing.
- Utilized Microsoft TFS to follow defects, report defects, monitor User Stories, approve
  pipelines, approve Change requests, add automation tests to branches of each sprint, and
  add tasks to track hours worked.

## IT Engineer Tester II

### Ericsson (2019 - 2020)

Ericsson is a leading telecommunication technology company, providing solutions for their hardware and appliances for management, sim-cards, administrations, ERP, automation procedures, etc.

- Analyzed requirements and user stories.
- Created and executed test cases.
- Developed test plans for Functional, Regression, Exploration, Smoke, and E2E testing.
- Tracked defects, errors, bugs, and glitches in the APIs, Web applications, and Database.
- Created automated test steps, plans, and scripts in Postman collections.
- Maintained the automated test plans and collections.
- Followed automation test scripts in pipelines in Gitlab.
- Ensured the maintenance of a Test Plan covering functional testing.
- Utilized Jira to track user stories, bugs, and tasks for hours.

# Languages

Spanish: Native English: Upper Intermediate

# **Education**

## Universidad Mariano Galvez (2014 - Present)

Currently Studying Systems Engineering and Computer Science

# Certifications & Other Courses

#### Udemy

- Selenium With Java and Cucumber (2021)
- JavaScript 2020: From Beginner to Professional (2020)
- Database Development SQL Server 70-762 (2020)

#### Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate

CertiProf (2020)

### Fundamentals of web development: Full Stack or Front-end

LinkedIn (2021)

## Mobile App Development

Google (2020)

## Contact Information

Phone Number: +502 4109-6172 / +1 909 680-0759

Email Address: <a href="mailto:stevenmedina781@gmail.com">stevenmedina781@gmail.com</a>

Alternative Email Address: steeven.medina@outlook.com